the the
pushing chain movement there.
Hold it.
You're free.
Raise the gate.
Shooter!
What's going to mean?
The underwriters field
that the accident has raised
some very serious safety
questions about the park.
That makes the investors
very, very anxious.
I had a promise to conduct a
very thorough, on-site inspection.
Hello, Kate's inspections.
They slow everything down.
I need to go over funding.
I'm slowing down even more.
I've already got you in Malcolm,
but they think he's too friendly.
They want Alan Grant.
Grant?
Well, you never get him out of one, Tara.
Loose, bus points.
Moo-chachos, engine the loose.
Why not?
Because grants like me.
He's a digger.
You can dream this.
Dr. Grant, Dr. Shatler,
we're ready to try again.
I had computers.
He's feeling it's mutual.
There we go.
Take a look.
Good boy.
How long does this year really take?
She'd bring in a media return.
She'd return to the ground, and the bone
bounces the image back, bounces it back.
This new program's incredible.
Two more years development, and
we won't even have to take anymore.
There's a fine amount.
It's a little distorted, but I
don't think it's a computer.
There's more than contraction
of the posterior neck ligaments.
The loss of raptor?
Yeah, it's good shape, too.
five, six feet high, I'm
guessing nine feet long.
Look at the extraordinary.
What'd you do?
You touched it.
It's not your greatest
number, so you can cut it.
You've got to do it for me.
And look at the half-moon
shape bones on the wrist.
There's no one of these
guys that don't have a fly.
Well, seriously.
All right.
Well, maybe dinosaurs
have more in common with
present-day birds than
they do with reptiles.
Look at the pubic bone
turned back with just like a bird.
Look at the vertebrae full of air
section hollows, just like a bird.
And even the word
raptor means bird of prey.
That doesn't look very scary.
More like a six-foot turkey.
I'm turkey, huh?
Oh, no.
OK.
I don't imagine yourself
in the rotation's period.
You get your first look at this
six-foot turkey as you enter a cleric.
It moves like a bird.
lightly bobbing his head, and you keep still
because you think that maybe his visual acuity is
based on movement like T-Rex, and he'll lose you
if you don't move, but no, not the laceraptor.
You stare at him, and
he just stares right back.
And that's when the attack comes,
not from the front, but from the side.
When the other two raptors,
you didn't even know were there.
Because Velociraptors are packed under.
You see, he uses coordinated attack
patterns, and he is out and forced today.
And he slashes at you with this.
Six-inch retractable claw,
like a razor on the middle toe.
He doesn't bother to fight
your jugular like a lion, say.
No, no.
He slashes at you here or here.
Or maybe across the
valley, spilling urine test.
The point is, you are alive
when they start to eat you.
So, you know, try to show a little respect.
Okay.
Hey Alan, if you wanted to scare the kid,
you could have pulled a gun out of me now.
Yeah, I know, kids.
You want to have one of those?
I don't want that kid, but a breed of
child, Dr. Grant, could be intriguing.
I mean, what's so wrong with kids?
Oh, yeah, they looked in noisy.
They're messy, they're expensive.
They smell?
They do not smell.
Some of them smell, baby smell.
What the hell do you
think you're doing in here?
We were saving that.
But today, I'll go and see it.
And who in God's name do you think you are?
John Hammond.
And I'm delighted to meet
you finally in person, Dr. Grant.
Still, I can see that my 50,000
a year has been well spent.
Okay, who's the jerk?
This is our paleo botanist, Dr. Sadler.
Sadler?
Ellie, this is Mr. Hammond.
I'm sorry about dramatic
entrance, Dr. Sadler, but...
I see sure.
But you have a drink.
We won't if we get warm.
Come along and sit down, sit down.
I'll just get a glass or two.
No, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no,
no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no,
Both of you.
I can tell instantly about people.
It's a gift.
I own an island of the coast of Costa Rica.
I've leased it from the
government, and I've spent the
last five years setting up a
kind of biological preserve.
Really spectacular, spared no expense.
Make the one I've got down
in Kenya, look like a pitting zoo.
And there's no doubt our attractions
will drive kids out of their minds.
And what are those?
Small versions of that, I don't know.
And not just kids, everyone.
We got to open next year.
That is if the lawyers don't kill me first.
I don't care for lawyers.
Do you?
Oh, we, uh...
I don't really know.
Well, I do.
I'm afraid there's a
particular pebble in March.
Who represents my investors?
Says that they insist on outside opinions.
What kind of opinions?
Well, your guy not
put to find a point on it.
I mean, let's face it, in your
particular field, you're the top minds.
And if I could just
persuade you to sign off on
the park, you don't
give it your endorsement.
Maybe even pen a wee testimony.
I could get back on schedule.
That would scare you.
Why would they care what we think?
The park is this.
It's right up your alley.
I tell you, why don't you come down
just at the pair of you for the weekend?
I'd love to have an opinion
of our paleo-battanist as well.
I've got a jet standing by a chotto!
Oh my god, I'm sorry,
this isn't possible, is this a.
.. We just dug up a
new skeleton tonight.
I can't see it by fully funding your dig.
And this is a very unusual
time for a further three years.
Where's the plane?
Yeah.
Okay.
Gotcha!
You shouldn't use my name.
Dodson, Dodson, we've got Dodson here.
Somebody cares.
Nice hat.
Let me try to look like a secret agent.
750.
Undolibrate 50,000 more
for each viable embryo.
That's 1.5 million if you get
all 15 species out of the island.
Oh, I'll get them all.
Remember, viable embryos, and
they'll use to us if they don't survive.
How am I supposed to transport them?
The bottom screws open.
Oh, my God.
It's cold and compartmentalized inside.
You get that so that's crazy.
Muslims can even check,
and if they want to, go on.
Is it up cool and inside for 36 hours?
No meant being.
The embryos have to be
back here in San Jose by then.
That's up to your guy on the boat.
Seven o'clock tomorrow
night on the East dock.
Make sure he gets it right.
How are you planning to beat security?
Well, I've got an 18 minute window.
18 minutes in your company
catches up on 10 years of research.
Don't get cheap on me, Dodson.
That was Hammond's mistake.
Will you two dig up dinosaurs?
Oh.
Try it, sir.
You'll have to get used to Dr. Malcolm.
He suffers from a deplorable exercise of
personality, especially for a mathematician.
Care, Titian.
Actually, if John doesn't subscribe
to Chaos, particularly when it
has to say about a little science
project, oh, it's a lot of Ian.
You've never been in sufficiently
explaining your concern.
Oh, John, John, John, because we
gave you the system of phase space.
a load if I may say so.
A fashionable number of countries.
That's what I'm going to do.
Dr. Sadley, Dr. Grant, you've heard
of, have you ever heard of cash there?
No.
No nonlinear equations.
Strange attractions.
Dr. Sadley, right?
I refuse to believe that you aren't
familiar with the concept of attraction.
I bring scientists you bring a long star.
There it is.
When she is, we have
to drop pretty fast, so
hold on, because
this can be just a little.
I'm still in here.
Look what I've landed by
the time they get me right.
Come on.
Oh, my God.
for 50 miles of perimeter
fence are in place.
I'm the concrete modes.
I'm the motion center tracking
systems, almost thereby relax.
Try and enjoy yourself.
Let's get something strange, John.
This is not a weekend excursion.
This is a serious investigation
of the stability of the aisle.
Your investors might
represent our deeply concerned.
48 hours from now, if they're
not convinced, I'm not convinced.
I shut you down, John.
In 48 hours, I'll be
accepting your apologies.
The city boos here.
And this species of veriformans
been extinct is the Cretaceous period.
I mean this thing is about this thing.
Why?
It's... it's a dinosaur.
You're dead.
You're crazy, son.
I bet you're dead.
I mean, we can just
tear up the little bucket.
I'm glad that it doesn't apply.
That totally runs.
It's a warm body creature.
This thing doesn't let you swarm.
This thing's got better.
25, 27 foot neck.
Rachiosa, 30.
We're going to make a
fortune with this place.
How fast are they?
Well, we clocked the
T-Rex at 32 miles an hour.
T-Rex?
You said you've got a T-Rex?
Uh-huh.
Say it again.
We have a T-Rex.
Dr. Grant, my dear Dr. Satch,
welcome to Jurassic Park.
They're moving in hurts.
They don't move in hurts.
How'd you do this?
Good day, good day, good day.
Now, the most advanced amusement
park in the entire world, incorporating
all the latest technologies, and
I'm not talking just about right.
Everybody has rights.
We've made living biological
attractions, so astounding
that they're captured the
imagination of the entire planet.
So what are you thinking?
We're out of a job.
Don't you mean extinct?
Why don't you all sit down?
Don't sit down.
Sit down.
Here he comes.
Oh, you're right.
Hello.
Hello, John.
Oh, yes.
I got lying.
Well, fine, fine.
I guess.
But how did I get here?
Well, let me show you first.
I'll need a drop of blood.
Your blood.
Right.
John, that hurt.
Relaxed John.
It's all part of the miracle of cloning.
Hello, John.
From what?
Low extraction has never
recreated intake DNA strain.
Not without an answer sequence, perhaps.
Good afternoon, John.
Do you know from what source?
Where do you get 100 and
your old dinosaur plants?
What?
Oh, but Mr. Deeley,
where did you come from?
From your blood.
Just one drop of your blood
contains billions of strands of DNA.
The building blocks of life.
A DNA strand like me is a
blueprint for building a living thing.
And sometimes animals that
went extinct millions of years ago,
like dinosaurs, left their
blueprints behind for us to find.
We just had to know where to live.
100 million years ago, there
were mosquitoes just like today.
Yeah, I'm just like today.
They fed on the blood of
animals, even dinosaurs.
Sometimes, after biting a
dinosaur, the mosquito would
land on the branch of a
tree and get stuck in the sap.
After a long time, the tree sap
would get hard and become fossilized
just like a dinosaur bone,
preserving the mosquito inside.
This fossilized tree
sample, which we call amber,
waited for millions of years
with the mosquito inside.
Until Jurassic Park scientists came along.
Using sophisticated
techniques, they extract
the preserved blood
from the mosquito end.
Bingo, dino dme.
A full DNA strain contains
three billion genetic cones.
If we looked at screens like
these once a second for eight hours
a day, it'd take two years to
look at the entire DNA strain.
It's that long.
It's full of holes.
Now that's where our geneticists take over.
Think in machine supercomputers and gene
sequencers break down the strain in minutes.
and virtual reality displays show our
geneticists the gaps in the DNA sequence.
We used to complete DNA of a frog,
the million holes, and complete there.
Cold!
And now, we can make a baby dinosaur.
This scar is only temporary.
It all has very dramatic music, of course.
Oh, my little macho, some of
you haven't been written yet.
And then, of course, the tumor is up.
It's overwhelming, John.
All right, are these characters autorotic?
No, we have no end of electronic theater.
Those people have the real
miracle work as a journalist.
I'm fertilized.
You're austrid yet.
And it's no way to make a hada.
How do you interrupt the cellular mitosis?
Can we see the unfertilized dance?
Oh, chop and chop.
Can't you stop these things?
I'm sorry, it's a kind of a ride.
I can't do that.
What?
Can they do that?
For reminder, the boat for the
mainland is leaving in 1900 out.
All personnel be asked
to dock complete at 1545.
There you are, man.
Oh, good day, sir.
It's turning the eggs.
Oh, perfect timing.
I don't pay pass before
I had to go to the boat.
Hey, man.
I didn't just tell me.
I insist on being here.
I'm there, boy.
Come on.
Come on, then.
There you are.
They've been from the first
creature they come in contact with.
That shit helps him to trust me.
I've been present for the birth of
every little creature who's ironed.
Surely not the ones that
have been bred in the wilds.
Actually, they can't breed in the wild.
The population control is
one of our security precautions.
There's no unauthorized
breeding in Jurassic Park.
Is that how you know they can't breed?
Oh, because all the animals
in Jurassic Park are female.
Oh.
Oh, we've engineered them that way.
But again, how do you
know they're all female?
Whether somebody got in the
park and pulled the dinosaur's skirts?
We control their chromosomes.
It's really not that difficult.
All vertebrate embryos are
inherently female anyway.
They just require an
extra hormone given at the
right developmental
stage to make them male.
We simply deny them that.
Do you know how them that?
John, the kind of controller
you're attempting is not possible.
Listen, if there's one
thing, the history of
evolution has tossed, that
life will not be contained.
Life breaks free, it expands the
new territories, and it crashes through
barriers painfully, maybe even
dangerously, but, well, there it is.
There it is.
You're implying that a group
composed entirely of female animals will
No, I'm simply saying
that life finds a way.
It's a species, is it?
It's a velociraptor.
The bread raptors.
As I must say, we laid
on lunch for you before
you set out into the
park, our gourmet ship.
What are they doing?
Feeding them.
Alejandro's prepared a delightful
menu for his chili and sea bass, I believe.
Shall we?
They should all be destroyed!
Ah-ha!
Robert, Robert Mouldo, my
game warden from Kenya.
This is an alarm and stomach rate, but it
was more about wraps of the honeymoon.
What kind of metabolism do they have?
What's their growth rate?
No leap of eight months,
and I do mean lethal.
I'm 100 most things that can hunt
you, but the way these things move.
A fast for a bypass?
Cheetah speed.
50, 60 miles per hour, if
they ever got out in the open.
And there is stone ifing jumper.
Yes, yes, yes.
That's why we're taking
extreme precautions.
They show intelligence.
With the brain cavity.
Even problem solving intelligence.
Especially the big one.
We've bred eight originally,
but when she came in, she
took over the pride and
killed all the two of the others.
That one.
When she looks at you, you
can see she's working things out.
That's why we have to feed them like this.
She had the more attacking the
fences when the feeders came.
The fences are electrified, right?
That's right, but they never
attacked the same place twice.
They were testing the fences
for weaknesses systematically.
They remember.
Yes.
Who's hungry?
Now that these attractions are ready yet of course but the park will open with the basic tour you're about
to take and then other rides will come on line six or twelve months after that absolutely spectacular
design the spare no expense we can charge anything we want two thousand a day ten thousand a day and people
will pay it and then there's the merchandise this park was not built to cater only for the super rich
Everyone in the world has
the right to enjoy these apples.
Sure.
They will.
What?
We'll have a coupon day or something.
Gee, the lack of humility before nature.
It's being displayed here.
Staggers.
Well, thank you, Dr. Malcolm.
But I think things are a little bit
different than you and I have fear.
Yeah, I know.
They're a lot worse.
Wait a second.
Now, we haven't even
seen the party on any of you.
Don't let them talk.
There's no reason.
No, I won't be here if you'll talk to.
I really do.
Don't you see the danger?
John inherent in what you're doing here,
genetic powers, the most awesome force the
planets have ever seen, but you wield
it like a kid that's found his dad's a gun.
It's hardly appropriate to start hurling.
If I may.
I'll tell you the problem with the
scientific power that you're using here.
It didn't require any
discipline to attain it.
You know, you read what others
had done, and you took the next step.
You didn't earn the
knowledge for yourselves,
so you don't take
any responsibility for it.
You stood on the shoulders of geniuses to accomplish something
as fast as you could, and before you even knew it you had,
you patented it, and packaged it and slapped it on a plastic
lunchbox, and now you're selling it, you're selling it well.
I don't think you're
giving us our due credit.
Our scientists have done things
which nobody's ever done before.
Yeah, yeah, but your scientists
were so preoccupied with whether
or not they could, they didn't
start to think that they should.
Colonels.
Condors are on the verge of extinction.
If I was to create a flock of condors on
this island, you wouldn't have any to say.
No, hold on.
This is some species that was obliterated
by deforestation or the building of a dam.
Dinosaurs had their shot, and
nature selected them for extinction.
I simply don't understand this a lot
I'd attitude, especially from a scientist.
How can we stand in the light of discovery
Oh, it's so great about discovery.
It's a violent, penetrative act that scars
what explores what you call discovery.
I call the rape of the natural world.
Well, the question is, how can you
know anything about an extinct ecosystem?
And therefore, how could you
ever assume that you can control it?
You have plants in this
building that are poisonous.
You pick them because they look good.
But these are aggressive living
things that have no idea what century
they're in, and they'll defend
themselves violently if necessary.
Dr. Grant, if there's one person here
who could appreciate what I'm trying to do,
It was just changed so radically,
and we're all running to catch up.
I don't want to jump to
any conclusions, but look.
Dinosaurs and men, two species
separated by 65 million years of
evolution, just been suddenly
thrown back into the mix together.
How can we possibly have the
slightest idea what to expect?
I don't believe it.
You're meant to come down here
and defend me against these characters.
And the only one I've got on my
side is the blood-sucking lawyer.
Thank you.
There you are.
You four are going to have a
spot of company out in the park.
Spend a little time with
our target audience.
Here you go!
Kids!
I love the friends.
We're good to see you.
Did you enjoy the helicopter?
Yeah, it's way down
and we all went right up.
OK, come away.
Lock too close to the cars.
I feel lovely.
I'm very glorious.
These will be a transport
for the afternoon.
No drivers.
No, no, no, no, no, no, no, no drivers.
But they're electric.
They're on on this track
in the middle of the road.
We're here, totally not polluting.
Top of the line.
Spare no expense.
It's an interesting city, mom.
You just touched the right part of the
screen, and it talks about what it means.
All right.
Thanks, darling.
You're all right in there.
Dr. Sattler, come with me.
Dr. Brown, come in the second car.
I'm your right with Dr. Sattler.
I read your book.
Oh, that's, that's great.
You were laughing
that I'm starting to burn.
And that's where they all went.
Well, there are a few species
made available on those lines.
Is it sure it all looked like birth to me?
I heard that there was this, um, meteor.
Um, hit the earth.
Someplace that in Mexico
made this big crater.
It's not.
Tim.
Tim, which car would you plan on your arm?
It's a one you are.
They're really about this thing
and on me, about this, um,
meteor, making all this heat, and
it made a bunch of diamond dust.
And that means the weather.
And it died because of the weather.
And then my teacher told me about
this other life I ran in backer, and
he... She said I should run with
you, because it'd be good for you.
I'm only just now.
I'm coming.
Everyone must be long.
I've got all the night
that you've hunted out.
National Weather Service
is tracking a tropical storm.
About 75 miles west of us.
Oh, yeah, yeah, yeah.
Why didn't I build an old lambda?
I'll keep an eye on it.
Maybe it'll swing south like the last one.
Great.
Stop the top, right?
Hold on to your butts.
I'll see you in the next one.
Bye!
Hey, look at him, you're not gonna fall.
Hey, hey, hey, hey, hey, hey, hey, hey, hey, hey, hey, hey, hey, hey, hey, hey, hey, hey, hey, hey, hey, hey, hey, hey, hey, hey,
hey, hey, hey, hey, hey, hey, hey, hey, hey, hey, hey, hey, hey, hey, hey, hey, hey, hey, hey, hey, hey, hey, hey, hey, hey, hey, hey,
hey, hey, hey, hey, hey, hey, hey, hey, hey, hey, hey, hey, hey, hey, hey, hey, hey, hey, hey, hey, hey, hey, hey, hey, hey, hey,
The voice in our hearing is Richard Kylie.
We spared no expense.
If you look to the right,
you will see a herd of the
first dinosaurs on our
tour called Dylophosaurus.
Dylophosaurus!
One of the earliest carnivores, we now
know Dylophosaurus is actually poisonous,
spitting its venom at its prey, causing
blindness and eventually paralysis.
allowing the carnivore
to eat at its leisure.
This makes stylophosaurus a beautiful
but deadly addition to Jurassic Park.
Down.
vehicle headlights are on it
and they're not responding.
They'll simply be running
out of car batteries.
Item 151 on the day's glitch list.
We have all the problems
with a major theme park and a
major suit and computers
aren't even on the feet yet.
Dennis, our lives are in your hands
when you have a bunch of fingers?
I'm totally unappreciated in my time.
You can run this whole park from this room
with minimal staff for up to three days.
You think that kind of automation is easy?
or cheap?
You know, anybody who can
network eight connection machines and
debug two million lines of
code for what I bid for this job?
Because if you can, I'd love to see them.
Sorry.
About your financial problems, Dennis.
I really am.
Are your problems?
Oh, you're right, John.
You're absolutely right.
You know, everything's my problem.
I will not get drawn into another
financial debate with you, Dennis.
I really will not have been
hardly any debate at all.
I don't blame people for the mistakes,
but I do ask that they pay for them.
Thanks, Dad.
Dennis.
The headlights.
Yeah, I'll debug the tool
program when they get back, OK?
OK?
It'll eat a lot of compute cycles.
We'll lose part of the system for a while.
And there's a finite amount of memory.
Again, use it for everything.
We're going to compile for half an hour.
Go ahead.
All of you.
We're approaching the Tyrannosaur product.
God creates dinosaurs.
God destroys dinosaurs.
God creates a man.
Man destroys God.
Man creates dinosaurs.
Dinosaurs.
Eat man.
Woman inherits the earth.
We'll try to kill the Rex now.
Keep walking the fence.
What's going to happen again?
He's going to eat the goat?
Excellent.
What's the matter, kid?
You never had lamb chops?
I happen to be a vegetarian.
Tearics doesn't want to be fat.
He wants to hunt.
Suppressed 65 million
years of gut instinct.
Not eventually you do might have
dinosaurs on your dinosaur tour, right?
Oh.
Oh, oh.
Yes.
I really hate that man.
Yeah.
See, the Tyrannus doesn't have
any set patterns or park schedules.
The essence of chaos.
I'm still not clear on chaos.
Oh, oh, did it simply deal with the
predictability and complex system?
The shorthand is the butterfly effect.
A butterfly can flap its wings
and puke came in Central Park.
He did rain instead of sunshine.
Wow.
And then I go in too fast.
And I go in too fast.
I did a fly by.
Give me that deglass and water.
We're going to conduct an experiment.
It should be still.
The car is bouncing up and down.
But that's OK. Just an example.
Now, put your hand
flat like a hieroglyphic.
Now, let's say you drop
waterfalls on your hand.
Which way is it dropping a roll off of
which way is it going to be over the summer?
Okay.
Now, freeze your hand, freeze your hand.
Don't move.
I'm going to do the same thing.
Start with the same.
Same place again.
Which way is going to roll up?
Let's see.
Same thing.
Why?
Because tiny variations are the
orientation of the hairs on your hands.
Yeah, I want to look at this.
They want to bud to stand in your
vessels imperfections in the skin.
I'm going to bed with you in the skin.
It's got to put my stuff in here.
I never repeat and
vastly affect the outcome.
That's for it.
I'm pretty familiar with it.
Hi.
Right there.
Look at this.
See?
I'm right again.
Nobody could have
predicted that Dr.
Grant would suddenly
jump out of a moving vehicle.
How in?
There's another example.
See, here I'm now by
myself talking to myself.
That's the case.
Stop the program.
I tell you how many times we need
locking mechanisms on the vehicle door.
My god was saying, there's this
other book by a guy named Bakker.
And he says that I'm
just restarting the movie.
He definitely did.
Is there anybody else who thinks
that we shouldn't be out here?
And his book was a lot
faster than nurse was like this.
He was Miss Foley.
Oh, it's great.
Hey.
Hey, look at this.
Wait, hey, watch.
Hey, come on, watch this.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
Everybody stay here.
Timmy!
Okay.
Come on, it's okay.
We'll now track the lines before me.
She's sick.
My favorite when I was a kid,
no, it's just nothing like a soul.
It's okay.
Necrovesicles.
It's interesting.
Thanks.
What are we symptoms?
We imbalance,
differentiation, labor, breathing.
It seems to happen about every six weeks.
Six weeks.
These are dilated.
They are.
It's OK.
I'll be damned.
It's pharmacological.
A local plant life.
Is this Westernian lilac?
Yes.
We know they're toxic, but
the animals don't eat them.
Are you sure?
Pretty sure.
There's only one way to be positive.
I'd have to see the dinosaurs dropping.
Yep.
You've got that.
That storm centre hasn't
dissipated or changed course.
We're going to have to
cut the tall shot of my frame.
Pick it up again tomorrow,
where we're left off.
Are you sure we have to?
It's not worth kicking the chance down.
Well, just downwinds 45 times
and they get back in the cars.
Yep.
Good.
Ladies and gentlemen,
last shot of leaving for
the dock, leaves in
approximately five minutes.
Drop what you're doing and leave now.
The head is one big pile of shit.
You're right, there's
no trace of lollig berries.
It's so odd though.
All right, so she's suffering
from nearly a toxicity.
Every six weeks.
Let's see.
She's, um, tenacious.
You have no idea.
You will remember to wash your
hands before you eat anything.
Doctors, if you please, I have
to insist that we get moving.
You know, if it's all right,
I'd like to stay with Dr.
Harding and finish
up with the triang.
Sure, I'm going to gas power
G. I can drop her with the
visitor center before I
make the fold of the others.
Great.
Then I'll catch up with
you if you want everyone.
You sure?
Yeah, I'm going to stay
with her a little longer.
No, no, no, listen, you've
got to give me the time.
I did a test one on this thing.
It took me 20 minutes.
I thought I could maybe push the 18,
but you've got to give me least 15 minutes.
Give me the 15 minutes.
Is it a vehicle that
we're turning to the rise?
So much for our first two now
shows and one will say tricella tops.
It could have been worse, John.
A lot worse.
Anybody want a soda or something?
Because I'm going up the machine,
I can get some of these something.
Because I'm penalty sweets,
and I think I'm going to get
some of these salty, I
thought maybe it's a good one.
Oh, I finished debugging the phones.
I was going to do, so I did.
I told me that, sorry, I debug the phones.
And I thought maybe I
should tell you that the
system is going to be
compiling for 18 to 20 minutes.
So some of the minor
systems, they might go on or
off for a while, but it's
not the worry about it.
So it's a simple thing.
I'm not getting kids.
Me.
Oh, oh, hell yeah, three.
I love kids.
Anything at all can and does happen.
Same with wives.
With that, man.
We're married?
Occasionally.
Yeah, I'm always on the
lookout for a future X Mrs. Melton.
Four, four, three, two, one.
That's odd.
What?
The door security
systems are shutting down.
Well, Nedry said a few systems
would go offline, didn't he?
By the way, Dr. Sadler.
She's not like available, is she?
Why?
I'm sorry.
You two are... Yeah.
Hey, what'd I touch?
Uh, we didn't touch anything we stopped.
What the hell?
What now?
Fences of failing all over the park.
Fine, Landry.
Check the vending machines.
No, no, there's still on.
Why the hell would he
turn the other ones off?
Access main program.
Access main security.
Please!
Get him!
Hate this hacker crap!
Oh, Nedry's back.
Okay, bitch.
The phones are out, too.
Where did the vehicle stop?
I didn't ask.
I wouldn't, maybe.
Kids get scared.
I must be scared.
I was scared.
I didn't say you were scared.
I know.
Whoa!
Hey, where did you find that?
It walks into my seat.
Are they heavy?
Yeah.
They're in there expensive, put them back.
Don't scare me.
Oh, cool.
My vision.
Maybe it's the power of
trying to come back on.
What is that?
He loves you.
Where does he think he's going?
When you got to go, you got to go.
and we had been right all the time.
Oh, fuck!
You're singing on my screen!
I'll catch you next.
You're okay.
All right.
Ten.
No move.
Can't see us if we don't move.
Yeah.
He took the lead.
Key check space minus O, key
checks off, safety space minus O.
He's turning the safety systems off.
He doesn't want anybody
to see what he's about to do.
Now, look at this next entry.
It's the kicker.
White rabbit object.
Whatever it did, it did it all.
But the key checks off, the
computer didn't file the keystroke.
So the only way to
find them now is to go
through the computer's
lines of code, one by one.
How many lines of code are there?
About two main.
Two million.
Yeah.
Robert, I, I wonder if
perhaps you would be good
enough to take a gas sheet
and bring back my gas sheet.
Sure.
I'm going with him.
John.
I can't get Jurassic Park back
online without Dennis Nedron.
There's the road.
This is a thing in a tiny, tiny thing
there and I don't tell this thing here.
My glasses.
I can afford more glasses.
You're trying to even do it!
Come on, Dennis!
Whoa!
That's nice.
Here we go.
Fire nice boy.
Nice boy.
Nice side of the cell.
Good.
I thought you were
one of your big brothers.
You're not so bad.
What do you want?
What do you want in my food?
Look at me.
I just felt down the hill.
I'm soaking wet.
I don't have any food.
I have no food on them.
I have nothing on it.
Like that, like that, like that, like that, like that, like that, like that, like that, like that, like that, like that, like that, like that, like that, like that, like that, like that, like that,
like that, like that, like that, like that, like that, like that, like that, like that, like that, like that, like that, like that, like that, like that, like that, like that, like that, like that, like
that, like that, like that, like that, like that, like that, like that, like that, like that, like that, like that, like that, like that, like that, like that, like that, like that, like that, like
that, like that, like that, like that, like that, like that, like that, like that, like that, like that, like that, like that, like that, like that, like that, like that, like that, like that, like that
Thank you.
Come on!
Come on, Max.
Listen, listen, Max.
I'm right here.
I'm gonna look after you,
but I have to go help your
brother, so I want you to
stay right here and wait for me.
Hey, Lucas.
You love it?
But that's not what I'm gonna do.
Okay?
Stay here.
Come here.
Come.
Here we are coming up.
Hi, come on.
Hi, trees.
Tim.
Why won't tell anyone to throw up just?
Just give me a hand.
It's just that coming out of treehouse.
It's dead of the villa treehouse.
No.
I think about climbing as
he never never looked down.
This is impossible.
So I'm going to help you put it.
Oh, no.
Go.
Okay.
Got him.
Well, we're back in the car again.
Well, at least you're out on the tree.
Where's the other car?
Out!
Dr. Grant!
Oh, yes!
Grant!
I think this was general.
I think this was too.
I think there'll be anywhere.
The fence is down.
It can wander in and out
of any pot of good bikes.
Give it a turn to get on.
Ian.
Remind me to thank
John for a lovely weekend.
George, you're a chance moving in.
Please, chances.
Anybody hear that?
It's a, um...
It's an impact term as what it is.
Fairly alarmed here.
Come on, come on, come on, come on.
We've got to get out of here.
Now, now, right now.
Let's go, go, go.
Let's go.
Hey.
Let's get out of here.
Let it go!
I think I'll have that on the tour.
Are you hearing this?
Come on, Tim.
Come on, hurry up.
That's, uh, the street.
Okay.
Come on, Tim.
That's okay.
Listen, trap here.
I hate trees.
They know by the me.
Oh, yeah, well, you
weren't in the last one.
Hey!
This is one of the sources,
and you know, brachiosers.
They're singing.
Hey!
The monsters come over here.
They're not monsters next, or just
animals, and these are herbivores.
That means the only eat vegetables, but
for you, I think they make an exception.
Well, I hate the other kind.
I just... do what they do.
I was there.
What do you know I can do now if you don't
have to pick up dinosaur bones anymore?
I don't know, I guess.
Guess we'll just have to evolve, too.
What do you call blind dinosaur?
I don't know.
Do you think he saw us?
What do you call blind dinosaurs dog?
You got me?
Do you think he saw us Rex?
Allen?
Yeah.
One of the dinosaurs
come back over all asleep.
What?
I'll stay awake.
All night?
All night.
I'm going to go.
They were all melting.
That comes okay for now.
I gave him a shot of morphine.
That'll be fine.
You better to get the children through
Jurassic Park than the dinosaur expert.
You know the first?
Traction I ever built when
they came down from Scotland.
It's a flea circus, a better coat lane.
Really?
Quite wonderful.
I had, uh, a wee trapeze and, uh,
uh, uh, a medical, um, got a-got a cell.
And a sea cell.
They don't move
motorized, of course, but,
uh, people would say
they could see the fleas.
Oh, I could see the fleas in the
mummy country, see the fleas.
I'm pleased, and I wear a
fleas and fleas on parade.
But this place, I wanted to show
them something that wasn't in the Lord.
Something that was real.
Something that I couldn't see him.
I mean, not the void of that.
But you can't thank through
this one, John, you have to feel it.
You're right, you're absolutely right.
Having negative was a mistake.
That's obvious.
We're overdependent on automation.
I can see that now.
Now, the next time everything's collectible,
creation is an act of sheer will.
Makes time that it be flawless.
It's still a flea circus.
It's all an illusion.
When we have control.
You never have control.
That's the illusion.
I was overwhelmed by
the power of this place.
But I made a mistake, too.
I didn't have enough respect
for that power, and it's out now.
The only thing that matters
now are the people we love.
Alan and Lex and Tim
John, they're out there
where people are dying.
So...
It's good.
It's bad dogs, man.
Go away!
It's okay.
It's regular.
It's a veggie source, Lex, veggie source.
It looks like it has a cold.
Yeah, maybe.
Am I touching?
Sure.
Just think of it as kind of a big cat.
Light cows.
Come on, girl.
You let up here, girl.
God bless you!
Yeah, oh great.
Now should never try anything new.
You just sit in the room and never
come out and play in your computer.
I'm a hacker.
That's what I said.
You're a nerd.
I'm not a computer nerd.
I prefer to be called a hacker.
God.
You know what this is?
The dinosaur egg.
The dinosaurs are breeding.
What?
We grabbed some dinosaurs with girls.
And Phoebe and DNA.
What's that?
Well, on the tour, the film said they used
frog DNA to fill in the gene sequence gaps.
They mutated the dinosaur genetic code.
and blended it with that of frogs.
Now, some West African frogs
have been on to spontaneously
change sex from male to female
in a single sex environment.
Malcolm was right.
Look.
I found a way
No, no, no, no, that's crazy.
You're out of your mind.
He's absolutely out of his mind.
Wait a minute.
What exactly would this mean?
We're talking about a calculated risk idea,
which is about the only option left to us.
We will never find the
command that never used.
He's covered his tracks far too well.
I think it's obvious now
that he's not coming back.
So shutting down the entire system is to
get somebody else because I won't do it.
Shut down the system.
He's the only way to wipe
out everything that he did.
Now, they understand
that all the systems will
then come back on their
original startup mode.
Correct?
Theoretically, yes, but we've never
shut down the entire system before.
May not come back on at all.
We get the phones back.
Yes, again, in theory.
What about the live scene contingency?
We could put that into effect.
What's that?
That is absolutely out of the question.
The licensing contingency
is intended to prevent the
spread of the animals in case
they ever get off the island.
Dr. Wu inserted a gene that creates a
single faulty enzyme in protein metabolism.
The animals can't manufacture
the amino acid licensing.
Unless they're
completely supplied with
licensing by us, they
slip into a coma and die.
People are dying.
Will you please shut down the system?
Hold on to your butt.
It's okay.
Look, see that?
It's all.
It worked.
Wait a minute, what do you mean it worked?
Everything's still off.
Well, maybe this shut
down trip to circuit breakers.
All we have to do is turn them
back on, reboot a few systems in
here, telephone, security doors,
half dozen others, but it worked.
Systems ready.
Where are the breakers?
Making it here, the other
end of the compound.
Three minutes, I can have
power back on the entire park.
Well, now that it's just to be safe, I
want everybody in the emergency bunker.
Until Mr. Arnold returns, and the
whole system's up and running again.
You tired, sir?
He's hot.
Oh, nice.
Nice.
Mr. Sims, just a little while.
Over that rise there.
Just?
Keep.
What is that?
Tim?
Tim, can you tell me what they are?
There.
Uh, uh, uh, uh, uh, gala.
Uh, gallon mics.
Are those, um, needing, uh, meat resources?
I don't think the wheeling
the uniform direction changes.
Just like a flock of
birds evading a predator.
They're, uh, they're flocking this way.
But you never look at
birds the same way again.
Yes.
I'm good now.
OK. Keep low and follow me.
It's blood.
It's actually... Oh, God.
Something went wrong.
Something's happened.
Something's wrong.
This is just a delay.
That's all it is.
All major theme parts have delays.
When they opened Disneyland
in 1956, nothing worked.
But John, if the pirates,
the Caribbean breaks
down, the pirates
don't eat the tourists.
I can't wait anymore.
Something went wrong.
Can I go get the power back on?
You can't just stroll down the road.
You know?
Well, don't let beat too hasty.
I mean, don't even go.
I'm going with you.
Now, this isn't going to be
just like switching on the kitchen
light, but I think I can follow
this and then talk you through it.
Right.
But, uh, it ought to be me really going.
Why?
Well, I'm, uh, on your own.
Look.
Come on, let's go.
We can discuss sexism and
survival situations when I get back.
Just take me through this step by step.
I'm on channel two.
The shutdown must have
turned over all the fences.
Dammit, he only had a new button
to miss with a wrapped up in his head.
Come on, this way.
No.
We can't.
Why not?
Because we're being hunted.
Oh, God.
Remember she's straight ahead.
It's all right.
Why can't let us run towards the shed?
Mr. Arnold!
I guess it means a power's off.
That's not funny.
No, it was great.
Damn it.
Wait a minute.
Yes, there should have been a
right turn back there somewhere.
What?
Oh, walk above you.
There should be a large public cable
and a pipe's landing in a safe direction.
Follow that.
OK.
Follow your pipe.
Timmy I can bet I can
climb over the top and be on
the other side before
you couldn't get to the top.
What would you give me?
What's back?
Come on guys, it's not a race.
I see the box.
Is this high voltage?
Yeah.
Okay.
There we go.
Over the top.
Take your time to him.
Let's go.
Come on.
Find your footing.
Really?
You can't throw the main switch by hand.
You've got to pump up the primer
handle in order to get the charge.
It's large, flat, and gray.
I'll hear it go, OK?
OK.
Charge.
Now, in other words, contact position.
There's a round, green button,
which says push to close.
Push to close.
OK.
I'm Ellie.
The red buttons turn on
the individual park systems.
Switch them on.
Come here.
Let's go.
Coming up, coming up to get you.
Got to get Tim.
OK.
I'm going to count three.
One.
Two.
It's not breathing.
I think we're back in business.
Oh, Mr. Arnold.
That's awesome.
I won't go.
Damn!
No, damn.
Good boy.
Great.
Hello.
OK. You have to find the others.
Get you to a doctor.
Max, you look after Tim?
Hey.
Here's all the sticking of.
Big Tim, the human piece of toast.
I'll be back soon.
I promise.
Come on!
It's just the two Raptors, right?
Are you sure the third one's contained?
Yes.
Almost a figure out how to open doors.
To me, what is it?
To the last raptor?
Ahh!
There's a new control room.
We can go over it up.
We gotta reboot the system first.
The door locks.
Ellie, boot off the door locks.
I know this.
It's how the files of the whole park.
It tells you everything.
This might be right by me.
This isn't right by me.
What works?
Fall insecurities systems.
Who name are we got?
Ground?
Mr. Hammond?
The phones are working.
Children are alive.
Are you on the fine?
Call the main leave.
Don't listen to damn helicopters.
This is going to come through the glass!
Get moved!
After careful consideration, I've
decided not to endorse your park.
So, bye.
Yeah.
You know what?
Thank you.
I'm sorry.
You.
you
I'm sorry.
Thank you.
you you
you